Now that you have dived a little deeper into neural networks.
NNを少し深く学んだので
Let's sort of how we can train them,
次はトレーニング方法や
some common pitfalls and something techniques to help
よくある落とし穴
In TensorFlow using the Estimator API, using a DNNRegressor,
Estimator APIを使用するTensorFlowでは DNNRegressorの使用は
is very similar to using a LinearRegressor,
LinearRegressorと似ていて
with only a few parameters for the code that need to be added.
追加すべきコードのパラメータはわずかです
We can use momentum based optimizers such as the default Adagrad,
既定のAdagradなど 慣性ベースのオプティマイザを使用できます
or we can try many others such as Adam.
Adamなどの他の方法も試せます
Also we now have to add a parameter named hidden units,
また隠れユニットというパラメータも必要です
which is a list.
これがリストです
The number of items in this list is the number of hidden layers and
このリストにある項目の数は隠れ層の数で
the values of each list item is a number of neurons for that particular hidden layer.
各リスト項目の値は特定の隠れ層の ニューロンの数です
You will also know there is a new parameter named dropout.
ドロップアウトという新しいパラメータも あります
We'll cover this and more in a few minutes.
これも少し説明しますが
But for now this is used to turn individual neurons on and
ここでは一般化の性能向上を目指して
off for each example in hopes of having better generalization performance.
各例の個々のニューロンのオンオフに 使用されます
Please look at the tentacle documentation for
設定できるパラメータの詳細は
the complete set of parameters you can configure.
関連文書を参照してください
These are all things that could be
これらはすべてハイパーパラメータ化 できるので
Back propagation is one of the traditional topics in an ML Neural Networks course.
誤差逆伝搬はML NNコースの 従来のトピックの1つです
But at some level,
しかし一部のレベルでは
it's kind of like teaching people how to build a compiler.
コンパイラの構築法の学習と同じで
It's essential for deeper understanding
深く理解するには必須ですが
but not necessarily needed for initial understanding.
最初の理解には不要です
The main thing to know is that there is an efficient algorithm for
導関数の計算に有効なアルゴリズムの存在と
calculating derivatives and TensorFlow will do it for you automatically.
TensorFlowがこれを自動で行うことを 知ってください
There are some interesting failure cases to talk about though,
ただし興味深い失敗例もあります
such as vanishing gradients,
勾配消失や
exploding gradients and dead layers.
勾配爆発や不感層などです
First, during the training process especially for deep networks gradients can vanish,
まず特に深いネットワークでの トレーニング課程で勾配が消失し
each additional layer in your network can successively reduce signal vs noise.
ネットワークの各層で相次いで信号対ノイズが 小さくなります
An example of this is when using
この例としては
As you begin to saturate you end up in
飽和を開始すると
the slope is getting closer and closer to approximately zero.
傾斜がほぼ0に近づいていきます
When you go backwards through the network during back prop,
誤差逆伝搬でネットワークを後退するとき
your gradient can become smaller and smaller because you're compounding
勾配が小さくなります 勾配が完全に消失するまで
all these small gradients until the gradient completely vanishes.
小さい勾配をすべて組み合わせるためです
When this happens your weights are no longer updating
これが起こると重みは更新されなくなり
and therefore training grinds to a halt.
そのためトレーニングは急停止します
A simple way to fix this is to use non saturating
簡単な修正方法はReLUや ELUなどの
non-linear activation functions such as ReLUs, ELUs, et cetera.
飽和しない非線形活性化関数を使用することです
Next, we can also have the opposite problem where gradients explode,
次に勾配爆発という逆の問題が 生じることもあります
by getting bigger and bigger until our weights gets so large we overflow.
重みが大きくなってオーバーフローするまで 勾配が大きくなるものです
Even starting with relatively small gradients,
比較的小さな勾配で始まっても
such as a value of two,
たとえば値が2でも
can compound and become quite large over many layers.
多くの層で組み合わさると非常に大きくなります
This is especially true for sequence models with long sequence lengths,
これは特に系列長が長い系列モデルに 当てはまります
learning rates can be a factor here because in our weight updates,
学習率も重要です 重みの更新では
remember we multiplied the gradient
勾配と学習率を掛けて
with the learning rate and then subtract that from the current weight.
その積を現在の重みから引くためです
So, even if the grading isn't that big with a learning rate greater than
そのため勾配が大きくなくても 学習率が1より大きいと
one it can now become too big and cause problems for us and our network.
重みが大きすぎてネットワークに問題が生じる 可能性があります
There are many techniques to try and minimize this.
これを最小限に抑える方法は多数あります
Such as weight organization and smaller batch sizes.
重みの整理やバッチサイズの縮小などです
Another technique is grading and clipping,
グレーディングとクリッピングもあります
where we check to see if the normal the gradient exceeds some threshold,
この方法では標準勾配が閾値を超えた場合
which you can hyperparameter or tune and if so,
ハイパーパラメータや調整を行えますが
then you can re-scale the gradient components to fit below your maximum.
その場合は勾配要素を変更して 最大値より小さくできます
Another useful technique is
他の便利な方法は
batch normalization which solves the problem called internal co-variance shift.
Internal Covariance Shift問題を 解決するバッチ正規化です
It's piece of training because gradients flow better.
これは勾配を改善するトレーニングの一部です
It also can often use a higher learning rate and might be able to get rid of dropout
また高い学習率を使用してドロップアウトを 排除できます
which slows competition down to its own kind of regularization due to mini batch noise.
これはミニバッチのノイズにより 競合を独自の正則化へと低速化させます
To perform batch normalization,
バッチ正規化を実施するには
first find the mini batch mean,
まずミニバッチの平均を見つけ
then the mini batch's standard deviation,
ミニバッチの標準偏差を探します
then normalize the inputs to that node,
次に入力をノードに対して正規化し
then scale and shift by gamma times X plus beta,
γ x X + βで段階的にシフトします
where gamma and beta are learned parameters.
ここでγとβは学習済みパラメータです
If gamma equals the square root variance of X and beta equals the mean of X,
γがXの分散の平方根でβがXの平均の場合
the original activation function is restored.
元の活性化関数が復元されます
This way, you can control the range of your inputs so that they don't become too large.
このように入力の範囲を制御できるので 大きくなりすぎません
Ideally, you would like to keep your gradients as close to one
勾配はできるだけ1に近づけることが理想です
So you don't compound and eventually underflow or overflow.
結合によるオーバーフローやアンダーフローを 避けます
Another common failure mode of grading descent is that real layers can die.
勾配降下のよくある失敗に 実層の不感化があります
Fortunately, using TensorBoard we can monitor
幸いにもTensorBoardを使うと
If using a candy and an estimator is automatically a scalar summary said for
キャンディやEstimatorの使用が自動的に
each GN hidden layer showing the fraction of
各GNの隠れ層のスカラサマリになると
zero values of the activations for that layer.
その層の活性化のゼロ値の割合を示します
ReLUs stop working when their inputs keep them in
入力がずっと負領域のままで
the negative domain giving their activation a value of zero.
活性化がゼロ値になる場合 ReLUは動作を停止します
It doesn't end there because then their contribution in the next layer is zero,
そこで終わりません 次の層の貢献がゼロのだからです
because despite what the weights are connecting it to
重みが次のニューロンに結合しているのに
A bunch of zeros come into the next neuron doesn't help it get into
大量のゼロが次のニューロンに入り
Then we perform back prop and their gradients are zero,
そこで誤差逆伝搬を行うと勾配はゼロになり
so we don't have the weights and thus training halts. Not good.
重みがなくなるためトレーニングは停止します 失敗です
We've talked about using Leaky or parametric ReLUs or even the slower ELUs,
Leaky/Parametric ReLUなどの使用を 説明しましたが
but you can also lower your learning rates to help stop
学習率を下げて
ReLu layers from not activating and not staying.
ReLU層の不活性化を阻止できます
A large gradient possibly due to too high of a learning rate can update
大きな勾配は学習率が高すぎることが原因で
the weights in such a way that no data point will ever activate it again.
重みが更新されても データポイントが再度活性化されません
Since the gradient is zero,
勾配がゼロなので
we won't update the weight to something more
合理的数値に重みを更新できず
reasonable so the problem will persist indefinitely.
問題はいつまでも続きます
Let's have a quick intuition check,
簡単な直観チェックを行いましょう
what will happen to our model,
有用な信号が2つあり
if we have two useful signals both
どちらも個々にラベルと相関性があるものの
independently correlated with the label but there are at different scales?
尺度が異なる場合 モデルはどうなるでしょうか？
For example, we might have
たとえば
If the feature for chicken stock is measured in liters,
チキンストックの特徴はリットルで測定され
but beef stock is measured in milliliters then
ビーフはミリリットルで測定されている場合
stochastic grading the scent might have a hard time converging well.
直感をグレーディングする確率変数が うまく収束しません
Since the optimal learning rate for these two dimensions is likely different.
この2次元の最適な学習率が異なるためです
Having your data clean and in a computationally helpful range
データをクリアにして 計算に役立つ範囲に入れることには
has many benefits during the training process of your machine learning models.
機械学習モデルのトレーニング過程において 多数の利点があります
Having feature value small and specifically zero
特徴値を小さくしてゼロ中心にすると
This is why batch normalization was helpful with exploding gradients
こうした理由でバッチ正規化は勾配爆発に 役立ちました
because it made sure to keep not just the initial input features,
最初の入力特徴だけでなく
but all of the intermediate features within
すべての中間特徴も健全範囲内に収め
a healthy range as not to cause problems with our layers.
各層に問題が起こらないようにしました
This also helps us avoid the NaN trap,
これでNaNトラップも回避できます
where our model can blow up if values exceed numerical precision range.
これでは値が数値精度範囲を超えると モデルが爆発します
A combination of features scaling and/or
特徴スケーリングと学習率低下の組み合わせで
Also, avoiding outlier values helps with generalization.
また異常値の除外も一般化に役立ちます
So detecting these perhaps the anomaly detection and
異常検出などで異常値を検出し
pre-processing them out of the data set before training can be a great help.
トレーニング前にデータセットから前処理で 除外できれば非常に役立ちます
Remember that there is no one best one size fits all method for all data.
どんなデータにも使える汎用的な方法は ありません
It is possible to think of good and bad cases for each of these approaches.
各方法について適切な事例と不適切な事例を 考えてみましょう
There are many methods to make our future value scale to small numbers.
特徴値のスケールを小さくする方法は 多数あります
First, there is linear scaling where you first find the minimum and maximum of the data.
線形スケーリングでは まずデータの最小値と最大値を見つけます
Then for each value,
次に各値について
we subtract the minimum and then divide by
最小値を減算し
This will make all values between zero and one,
これですべての値が0と1の間になります
where zero will be the minimum and one will be the maximum.
0が最小値で1が最大値です
This is also called normalization.
これは正規化とも呼ばれます
There is also hard caping or clipping,
ハードキャッピング（クリッピング）もあります
where you set a minimum value and a maximum value.
ここでは最小値と最大値を設定します
For instance, if my minimum value is
たとえば最小値を-7と設定し
then all values less than negative seven will become negative seven,
-7未満の値はすべて-7になり
and all values greater than 10 will become 10.
10を超える値はすべて10になります
Log scaling is another method where you apply the logarithm function to your input data.
ログスケーリングという方法では 対数関数を入力データに適用します
This is great when your data has huge range and you want to
これが役立つのは データの範囲が広いため
condense it down to be more about just the magnitude of the value.
これを凝縮させて 値の大きさだけにしたいときです
Another method which we just talked about with batch normalization is standardization.
先ほど紹介したバッチ正規化のもう1つの方法は 標準化です
Here, you calculate the mean of your data and the standard deviation.
ここでデータの平均と標準偏差を計算します
Once you have these two values,
この2つの値がわかったら
you subtract the mean from every data point and then divide with the standard deviation.
平均を各データポイントから引き 標準偏差で割ります
This way, your data becomes zero centered because your new
これで新しい平均が0になり
Of course, there are many other ways to scale your data.
他にもデータのスケーリング方法は多数あります
Which of these is good advice if my model is experiencing exploding gradients?
モデルに勾配爆発が生じた場合の推奨事項は？
The correct answer is A, B,
正解はA、B、C、Dです。
which can happen when our learning rate gets too high.
これが生じるのは学習率が高すぎるときです
This can lead to a whole bunch of other issues like
これは数値安定化や発散など
numerical stability, divergence and [inaudible].
他にもさまざまな問題を引き起こします
Therefore, lowering the learning rate to find that nice Goldilocks zone is a great idea.
そのため学習率を下げて適切なゴルディロック ゾーンを見つけることが必要です
Weight authorization can also help in
この点において重みの正則化も役立ちます
which should make it harder for gradients to explode.
勾配爆発を起こりにくくします
Also, applying gradient clipping can ensure
また勾配クリッピングを適用しても
that gradients never get beyond a certain threshold that we set.
勾配が特定の閾値を超えないようにできます
This can help mitigate somewhat a higher learning rate.
学習率の上昇をある程度緩和できます
However, with a high enough rate,
しかし高率のままだと
it can still drive the weights to very high values.
重みが非常に高くなる可能性があります
Batch normalization can help
バッチ正規化は
the intermediate inputs at each layer stay within a tighter range,
各層の中間入力が狭い範囲に留まるため
so there will be a much reduced chance of weights growing out
重みが範囲外まで大きくなる確率が大幅に減り
There are many methods to treat exploding gradients,
勾配爆発の処理方法は多数あるので
so you don't need a doctor to help.
医者の助けは不要です
All you have to do is experiment with these tools and see what works best.
こうしたツールを試して最適な方法を 探せばいいのです
Another form of regularization that helps build
より一般化されたモデルの構築に役立つ 他の正則化には
To use dropout, I add a wrapper to one or more of my layers.
ドロップアウトを使うには層にラッパーを 追加します
Intenser flow, the parameter you pass is called dropout,
TensorFlowでは渡すパラメータが ドロップアウトで
which is the probability of dropping a neuron
ネットワークからニューロンを
temporarily from the network rather than keeping it turned on.
一時的にドロップアウトさせる確率です
You want to be careful when setting this number because
この数値の設定には注意が必要です
for some other functions that have a dropout mechanism,
ドロップアウトのある他の関数では
they use keep probability,
キープ確率を使用します
which is a complement to drop
これはドロップ確率を補うもの
You wouldn't want to intend only a 10 percent probability to drop,
確率を10%だけ落とすつもりが
but actually are now only keeping 10 percent in your nodes randomly;
ノードの10%のみをランダムにキープすると
that's a very unintentional sparse model.
意図的でないスパースモデルになります
So, how does dropout work under the hood?
ドロップアウトの内部での仕組みは？
Let's say we set a dropout probability of 20 percent.
ドロップアウト確率を20%に設定した場合
This means that for each forward parsed to the network,
ネットワークに前方パスされたものでは
the algorithm will roll the dice for each neuron and the dropout wrapped layer.
ニューロンとドロップアウト ラップ層がサイコロで決まります
If the dice roll is greater than 20 and the neuron will stay active in the network,
サイコロの目が20より大きく そのニューロンがアクティブの場合
[inaudible] roll will be dropped,
脱落し
and output a value of zero regardless of its inputs
入力に関係なくゼロ値が出力されるため
effectively not adding negatively or positively to the network.
事実上ネットワークには何も追加されません
Since adding zero changes nothing and simulates to the neuron doesn't exist.
ゼロを追加しても何も変わらず ニューロンへの刺激は存在しません
To make up for the fact that each node is only kept some percentage of the time,
各ノードがわずかな時間しかキープされない 事実の埋め合わせに
the activations are scaled by one over
活性化のスケーリングを
one minus the dropout probability or in other words,
1÷ (1-ドロップアウト確率)
one over the keep probability during
つまり （1÷トレーニング中のキープ確率）で行うと
training so that it is the expectation value of the activation.
それが活性化の期待値になります
When not doing training without having to change any code,
トレーニングを行わず コードの変更も不要な場合は
the wrapper effectively disappears and the neurons in
ラッパーは事実上消え
The awesome idea of dropout is that it is essentially creating an ensemble model,
ドロップアウトの考えでは 基本的にアンサンブルモデルが構築されます
because for each forward pass there is effectively
前方パスでは事実上
a different network that the mini batch of data is seen.
データミニバッチは異なるネットワークを 参照します
When all this is added together in expectation,
これらをすべて予測に追加すると
it is like I would train two to the n neural networks,
2～nのNNをトレーニングすることになります
where n is the number of dropout neurons,
nはドロップアウトニューロン数です
and have them working in an ensemble similar to
アンサンブルの作動は多数の ディシジョンツリーが
a bunch of decision trees working together in a random forest.
ランダムフォレストで協力するのと似ています
There is also the added effect of spreading out
また信号の大部分をネットワークの
the data distribution of the entire network,
1本のブランチに向かわせるのではなく
rather than having the majority of
ネットワーク全体の
the signal favor going along one branch of the network.
データ分布に広がる相加的効果もあります
I usually imagine this as diverting water in a river or stream with multiple shunts or
これは複数の分岐やダムを使って川の水を 迂回させ
dams to ensure all waterways eventually get some water and don't dry up.
全水路に水が行き渡って 干上がらないようにするのと同じです
This way, your network uses more of its capacity since
この方法は信号がネットワーク全体に 均等に流れ
the signal more evenly flows across the entire network and thus,
ネットワークはその容量の多くを使用します
you'll have better training and generalization without
そのためトレーニングと一般化を適切に行え
large neuron dependencies being developed in popular paths.
ニューロンも人気のパスに大きく依存しません
Typical values for dropout are between 20 to 50 percent.
ドロップアウトの標準値は20～50%です
If you go much lower than that,
これを大幅に低くすると
there is not much effect from the network since you are rarely dropping any nodes.
ノードのドロップアウトが滅多に起こらず 効果が低下し
If you go higher,
高すぎてもトレーニングは行われません
You also want to use this on larger networks because there is
これは大きなネットワークでも使用できます
more capacity for the model to learn independent representations.
モデルが独立した表現を学習できる 容量があります
In other words, there are more possible pass for the network to try.
つまりネットワークが試せるパスが多くあります
The more you drop out,
ドロップアウトを多くして
therefore the less you keep,
キープを少なくすると
the stronger the regularization.
正則化が強化されます
If you set your dropout probability to one,
ドロップアウト確率を1に設定すると キープは0になり
and outputs a zero activation.
ゼロ活性化が出力されます
During backprop, this means that
誤差逆伝搬では
the weights will not update and this layer will learn nothing.
重みは更新されず この層は何も学習しません
If you set your probably to zero,
この確率を0に設定すると
then all neurons are kept active and there is no dropout regularization.
全ニューロンが活性化し ドロップアウト正則化はありません
It's pretty much just a more computationally costly way to
ドロップアウトラッパーのないこの方法では
not have a dropout wrapper at all because you still have to roll the dice.
サイコロが必要になるため 計算コストが高くなります
Of course, somewhere between zero and one is where you want to be.
もちろん0と1の中間が理想的な位置です
Specifically with dropout probabilities between 10 to 50 percent,
ドロップアウト確率は10～50%が理想的で
where a good baseline is usually starting at 20 percent and then adding more is needed.
適切なベースラインは20%から始まり 必要なら追加します
There is no one-size-fits-all dropout
全モデルやデータ分布に使える
probability for all models and all data distributions.
汎用的なドロップアウト確率はありません
Dropout acts as another form of blank.
ドロップアウトは＿＿として機能します
It forces data to flow down blank paths so that there is a more even spread.
データがより均等に広がるように データを＿＿パスに流します
It also simulates blank learning.
また＿＿学習をシミュレートします
Don't forget to scale the dropout activations by the inverse of the blank.
＿＿の逆数でドロップアウトの活性化を スケーリングします
We remove dropout during blank.
＿＿中はドロップアウトを除外します
The correct answer is E. Dropout act is
正解はEです ドロップアウトは
another form of regularization so the model can generalize better.
正則化として機能するため モデルの一般化が向上します
It does this turning off nodes with a dropout probability,
これを行うには ドロップアウト確率でノードをオフにし
which forces data to flow down multiple paths so that there is a more even spread.
データがより均等に広がるように データを複数パスに流します
Otherwise, data and the activations
そうしないとデータと活性化は
associated with it can learn to take preferential paths,
優先的なパスを取るようになり
which might lead to under training of the network as
ネットワークのトレーニング不足につながり
a whole and provide poor performance on new data.
新しいデータの性能が低下します
Dropout also simulates ensemble learning by creating an aggregate of
ドロップアウトは2～nのモデルの集約を 作成して
two to the n models due to the random turning off of nodes for each forward pass,
アンサンブル学習をシミュレートし 前方パスのノードを無作為にオフします
where n is the number of dropout nodes.
nはドロップアウトノード数です
Each batch sees a different network,
バッチは別のネットワークを見るので
so the model can't overfit on the entire training set much like a random forest.
モデルはトレーニングセット全体で 過学習になりません
Don't forget to scale the dropout activations by the inverse of the keep probability,
キープ確率の逆数でドロップアウトの 活性化をスケーリングします
which is one minus the dropout probability.
キープ確率=1-ドロップアウト確率
We do this with the expectation on the node will be scaled correctly during training,
これはノードの予測で行え トレーニング中にスケーリングされます
since for inference, it will always be on;
推測の場合は常にオンになっており
since we remove dropout during inference.
推測中はドロップアウトを除外するためです